

Sahas Arora



Summary



I'm a Computer Science graduate with a knack for full stack web development using the MERN stack. Moreover, I have experience in mobile-application development using React Native. I'm an avid learner and can adapt to different technologies and environments efficiently.



Education

2016-01 -2018-08 San Francisco State University, B.S Computer Science

2013-09 -2014-09

BITS-Pilani, Dubai Campus



Experience

2019-01 present

Web Developer

Tessora LLC

• Responsible for regular development and maintenance of www.tessoraclothing.com

2016-07 -2016-08

Project Intern

EY

Summer Project intern for the Tax Department at Ernst & Young, Gurgaon, India.



Projects

"Survey Me This" (https://enigmatic-springs-23046.herokuapp.com/)

- A full-stack web application that allows a user to create surveys and send them as an email to any number of people for feedback purposes.
- Built the application using the MERN stack.
- Implemented mockup Client Side Billing using Stripe API.
- Authentication of the application was implemented using Google Oauth and Javascript's PassportJS library.
- Deployed the application on Heroku.

"Weather Me This"

- A weather based application that fetches a graphical representation of the average temperature, pressure and humidity of a city that the user searches for.
- Built the application using Javascript's React Library and Redux middleware.
- The weather data was retrieved using the Weather API from OpenWeatherMap.
- The graphical representation was implemented using React's SparkLines component.

"Fetch Me The Repositories"

- A web application that fetches a list of a user's public repositories from GitHub, as well as allowing the user to filter the list through keywords.
- The application was built using Javascript's React Library.
- The repository data was retrieved using GitHub's REST API v3.

"Top 5"

- A Yelp based application that uses the Yelp Fusion API to fetch a list of events happening in the city that the user searches for.
- Built the application using Javascript's React Library and Redux middleware.
- The user is able to see a description, location (GoogleMapsAPI) and the cost of entry for the listed events.

"Fetch Me This in HD"

- A image viewing web-application that fetches a list of HD images based on a user's search query.
- The application was built using Javascript's React library.
- The HD images were retrieved using the Unsplash Image API.

"Youtube Replica"

- A Youtube mockup application that was built using Javascript's React library.
- Retrieved the data using the Youtube Data API.

"Environmental Hazards- Reporting and Management"

- The web application was built using the LAMP software stack and the Django web framework.
- The front-end was implemented using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.



Address

San Francisco, CA

Phone

4159964772

E-mail

sahasarora@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/sahas-arora

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sahasaror



Technical Skills

Javascript

ReactJS

NodeJS

ExpressJS

Redux

React Native

MongoDB

GraphQL

MySQL

Kubernetes

Docker

HTML

CSS

CSS Flexbox

Python

Django



Courses

Data Structures with Java

Machine Structures

Web Penetration Testing and Bug bounties

Parallel Computing with NodeJS

Operating Systems with C

Software Development with Android Studio

Programming Languages with C++, Ruby, Prolog and Scheme

Linear Algebra

Database Management Systems with MySQL

Software Engineering using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Python(Django)

Cloud Computing using AWS, GCS and NodeJS